<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<site>
    <article>
        <articleTitle>5 Reasons You Should Consider Building a Native Mobile App</articleTitle>
        <articleBody>&lt;p&gt;The buzz around mobile has been around for a while and isn&amp;#8217;t going anywhere, and with good reason. When over 90% of adults have their mobile phone within arm&amp;#8217;s reach 24/7, it&amp;#8217;s apparent that as a society, we&amp;#8217;ve become largely dependent on our mobile devices. I bet the last time you forgot your phone at home, you felt like a part of you was missing, didn&amp;#8217;t you? Well, you&amp;#8217;re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;With the population spending more and more time on their mobile devices, businesses can no longer afford to ignore their mobile experience. With an unlimited amount of information at their fingertips, consumers expect the ability to quickly access whatever info they need at that moment. And that&amp;#8217;s not just limited to consumers. In B2B environments, business users are researching products and services on their smartphones, and performing tasks that would typically be done on desktops.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft  wp-image-674&quot; alt=&quot;mobileapp-bannerleft&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/mobileapp-bannerleft.jpg&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This requires a different approach to strategizing for mobile, a mobile-first approach. The question is no longer &amp;#8220;should I build a responsive site or a native mobile app?&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s not a matter of one versus the other. Businesses today need to have a mobile friendly website, period. It&amp;#8217;s what your audience expects.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The question now becomes, &amp;#8220;is mobile web enough?&amp;#8221; To bring your customer engagement to the next level, it&amp;#8217;s a good idea to consider a native mobile app. If you&amp;#8217;re still not convinced, here are five advantages of mobile apps that makes the UX superior:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;ol&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 13px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better handling of touch, gestures, and swipes&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; Side to side swiping, while very popular on mobile apps and desktop sites, doesn&amp;#8217;t work as well on mobile websites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faster and more responsive&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; While mobile sites download the experience and data for each page through verbose HTML, mobile apps already contain most of the experience definition and only need to download the data&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to continue where you left off&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; Mobile apps allow users to carry on tasks that span over long periods of time without having to log back in each time&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tighter device integration&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; Mobile apps are much better equipped at handling features like geo-location, camera, and push notifications. While HTML5 is capable of supporting some of these device integrations, it&amp;#8217;s not to the same degree and is often a power drainer&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration with other apps&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; It&amp;#8217;s much easier and seamless to launch from one app to another app, than from an app to a mobile web app (take using your Facebook login to login to Pinterest for example)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Well, there you have it, five advantages that native mobile apps have over their mobile web counterparts. Of course, this doesn&amp;#8217;t mean everyone should go and replace all their web apps with native apps. Each business still needs to determine what works best for them. But this provides some areas for consideration the next time you&amp;#8217;re trying to decide whether or not to build that mobile app!&lt;/p&gt;</articleBody>
        <dateCreated>2015-06-12T13:27:16</dateCreated>
        <dateModified>2015-06-12T13:30:20</dateModified>
        <categories>
            <categoryId>1</categoryId>
            <categoryId>5</categoryId>
        </categories>
    </article>
    <article>
        <articleTitle>Building Engaging Customer Experiences Powered by MongoDB</articleTitle>
        <articleBody>&lt;p&gt;This spring and summer, the MongoDB Road Show stops in over 20 cities across the country to educate users on how MongoDB can be used to build modern business apps to improve the customer experience and accelerate time to market. Rivet Logic sponsored several of the cities and presented on the topic of building engaging customer experiences with MongoDB, discussing how a modern database can be used to better leverage existing data to derive business value. The next MongoDB Road Show is this Thursday, July 10, in San Francisco!&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Organizations Need&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Organizations seeking to build engaging customer experiences on the Web often have a similar set of goals. To start, they want to increase user adoption by providing an engaging experience that brings value to the end-user. This can lead to increased customer retention, allowing organizations to create loyal customers who can then become their own brand ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Moreover, organizations want to capitalize on their customers&#8217; and users&#8217; creativity and innovation by seamlessly weaving in the ability to collaborate, interact, and share into every aspect of the user experience. Businesses find the quality of this type of engagement to be particularly beneficial, due to its unpredictability. However, to enhance the value of these interactions, users need a motivator, meaning organizations need to create high quality content that&#8217;s personalized and targeted to each user&#8217;s needs.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While personas are great and have worked well to capture general types of users, in reality, users think of themselves more as individuals, with evolving interests over time. Organizations are now faced with delivering personalized experiences beyond a persona level and at an individual level.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#8217;s the Problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;However, many organizations are having a hard time with this fine-grained personalization, and it&#8217;s largely due to the limiting technology they&#8217;re working with. IT teams are often faced with seemingly &#8220;impractical&#8221; features that business teams are requesting.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Organizations today are using separate systems like standalone content apps &#8211; blogs, forums, wikis, &#8211; commenting engines, traditional databases, and BI tools to enable user interaction and collect and analyze information about them. The quality of user interactions is largely driven by the quality of the user-generated content being collected and analyzed. However, since much of this valuable customer data is silo&#8217;d in disparate systems, it&#8217;s not allowing businesses to effectively leverage their existing data.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While many have attempted to find workarounds for this, there hasn&#8217;t been any real success in creating a coherent rich user interaction data set that brings value to all the delivery use cases available. For example, when a user joins the comment thread of a blog entry, they are unaware of the possibility of a forum thread that is discussing the same topic. In addition, these solutions are typically backed by traditional databases, which requires changing of the infrastructure to accommodate new use cases, posing a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fact is, the various types of interactions that exist today are disjointed, resulting in redundancy and little chance of connecting and leveraging them. It&#8217;s critical that we make these interactions context-aware, and the only way of effectively doing so is to have a holistic view of all the user-generated content that&#8217;s being collected, while also allowing the interactions to cross application boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pillars of a Good Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Successful solutions that meet these challenges must adhere to the following pillars:&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt; &#8211; The solution must be implemented using technology agnostic building blocks. Being a certain type of shop (.Net, PHP, Windows, etc.) constrains organizations from using the right tools for the job. Using technology agnostic building blocks as the underlying infrastructure allows organizations to innovate and improve their business without being held back by technology.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability&lt;/strong&gt; &#8211; The solution must be scalable without sacrificing performance. There are many platforms out there that claim to be scalable, but what good is that when scaling means long page load times?&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visibility&lt;/strong&gt; &#8211; It&#8217;s also extremely important to be able to know and see the overall picture and have a holistic view of user interactions that isn&#8217;t so low-level where it prevents you from seeing what they are doing (as is the case with auditing services).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insight&lt;/strong&gt; &#8211; Lastly, when you have rich, contextual data available in one place, organizations need to be able to leverage that information, innovate and provide new features, capability, and value to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;</articleBody>
        <dateCreated>2015-05-22T10:00:06</dateCreated>
        <dateModified>2015-05-22T10:17:30</dateModified>
        <categories>
            <categoryId>2</categoryId>
        </categories>
    </article>
</site>